Let’s head into the final levels of exploit-exercises protostar.
这些级别稍微有点发达，而且是在非常简单的可编程级别上。
CTF challenges.
Let’s have a look at final level 0.
网络设置基本上与以前的挑战相同，因此如果您是
不熟悉这些自定义功能，您应该在
figure out what they do.
因此，当客户端连接到运行在端口2995上的服务时，它将调用此函数
get_username.
This function has a local 512 byte big buffer which is overwritten with 0.
Then gets is used to read data from the user into the buffer.
And as we have learned many episodes ago, gets is a dangerous function.
So this is obviously our buffer overflow.
然后它检查是否有换行符或回车符，如果有，它将用覆盖换行符或回车符
a 0.
After that is a loop, which will go over the buffer and call toupper on every character.
Then the function returns.
这意味着我们应该能够覆盖这个函数的返回指针并重定向
code execution.
我们只有一个问题，那就是我们将用于溢出的数据将被转换
to uppercase.
这意味着我们的外壳代码，以及我们用来覆盖指令指针的地址。
on the stack have to not change when toupper is used.
Meaning, you cannot use lower-case ascii characters.
或者有没有一个技巧可以让我们绕过这个限制？
Let’s think about this and work our way backwards.
So what condition has to be true in order that toupper is not used on our input.
Well the for loop uses strlen to determine on how many bytes it will do this.
And strlen counts all bytes until in finds a null byte.
所以如果我们设法在实际溢出和shellcode之前得到一个空字节，
we would be fine.
Ok, how could we get a null byte in there.
如果你查看Gets的手册页，你会看到，它会读取所有内容，直到
newline or EOF.
This means gets will have no issue of reading a null-byte.
Easy.
So we can completly ignore the to uppercase stuff.
出于创造性的原因，您还可以滥用
carriage return.
假设输入将使用strcpy，因此也将以空字节停止，您可以使用
a carriage return instead, which will then afterwards get replaced by a null byte.
So that would also work.
缓冲区是512字节大，所以让我们使用knwoledge创建一个简单的
concept buffer overflow.
We can use python with -c, to directly write a short script in the argument.
所以我们可以打印510个小写字母A，然后我们可以看到它们被修改了。
to be uppercase.
然后我们附加一个空字节，继续使用一个典型的字母表，这样我们就可以识别
to overflow the instruction pointer.
我们也可以把字母表改成小写，以证明它不会被转换成大写。
after the nullbyte.
和以前的网络挑战一样，我们可以连接到端口2995上的服务
with netcat.
So we can simply pipe the output of our python one-liner to netcat as well.
We don’t see the output “No such user… “ like before.
代码告诉我们，它将在主返回之后被打印，因此我们可以假设
we successfully overwrote the instruction pointer and crashed the program.
但是我们现在如何调试它呢？
如果你看一下原恒星虚拟机的描述，你会在这里看到一个标题。
called core files.
It says that the filename pattern is set to /tmp/ something.
This means that core dumps are stored in tmp.
And when we have a look at the content of /tmp/ we will see a core file we just produced.
They belong to root, so let’s switch to root so we can work with them.
但是什么是核心文件？
Let’s ask the linux manual with `man core`.
某些信号的默认动作是使进程终止并产生
核心转储文件，包含进程内存图像的磁盘文件。
of termination.
这听起来不错，如果我们得到了它崩溃时的记忆状态，我们应该能够
to get a lot of information about our buffer overflow.
此图像可在调试器（例如，gdb（1））中用于检查程序的状态。
at the time that it terminated.
哦，哇，我们可以用gdb来看看这些，我们已经非常熟悉如何
use gdb.
A list of the signals which cause a process to dump core can be found in signal(7).
Ok, interesting.
显然，进程收到了一个信号，因为它确实产生了一个核心文件，对吗？
So to understand this properly, let’s also try to understand what signals are.
注意信号后括号中的7，这对于参考正确的页面很重要。
about signal in the manual.
so `man 7 signal`.
Let’s have a look at the standard signals further down.
Linux supports the standard signals listed below.
Several signal numbers are architecture-dependent, as indicated in the "Value" column.
Mhh, so signals can be different on different architectures.
因此，如果它是一个Intel、ARM或SPARC处理器，这可能会有所不同，bug通常
这告诉我们，信号可能与非常低级别的CPU和硬件有关。
features.
Let’s have a look at the list of signals.
例如，sigint是一个多次使用的信号，它是来自
the keyboard, this happens when you press control+C.
或者记住，当你跳入无效的代码时，你有时是如何得到非法指令的，
a SIGILL, that’s also a signal.
很明显，这一定是由CPU触发的，它无法理解
instruction.
Or our favorite syscall, SIGSEGV, a segfault.
从illigel内存引用触发，例如当您跳转到不存在的
memory.
Or try to write to non existing memory.
Which obviously is also triggered by low level hardware when you try to execute bad stuff.
这里的这一行也很有趣：信号sigkill和sigstop不能被捕获、阻止，
or ignored.
This means most of these signals can be caught by the process.
在GDB中运行一个进程时，您实际上也经历过这种情况，但是您忘记了
若要设置断点且进程正在运行，可以使用ctrl+c返回
into gdb.
您向进程发送了一个sigint，该进程将信号处理程序设置为
catch it and perform a different action.
So signals are kind of like interrupts for processes by the kernel.
某些事件（如内存访问失败、按ctrl+c或同时终止进程）会导致
the kernel to send a signal to a process.
未处理的信号通常会导致进程死亡，但进程也可以设置信号
handlers to perform certain actions when it receives these signals.
So.
在我们的例子中，当我们在堆栈上溢出EIP时，函数返回一个分段错误
is raised and a signal is triggered.
The process doesn’t handle it and is killed by the kernel.
同时创建一个核心转储文件来保存导致
this signal.
So now let’s use gdb to see what happened.
像前面一样，只需将二进制文件指定为第一个参数，然后添加核心文件
file as a second argument.
当gdb打开时，会立即看到进程由于
signal 11, a segmentation fault.
We can also look at the registers and see the value of eip.
And those are definitely our characters we have entered.
We can also explore the stack with examining the stack pointer.
You can see that having these core files is extremely useful.
现在我们知道哪些字符导致了溢出，现在我们可以计算到
instruction pointer on the stack.
Another way to debug this further is to use gdb to attach to the already running process.
Make sure you are root.
Simply find the process id and call gdb with -p and the pid.
As you can see the process is currently in accept waiting for a client to connect.
But when we send our PoC overflow, we don’t see a segfault.
这是因为如果您还记得，这个过程会创建一个分叉，一个新的过程，来处理
client.
And we always stay in the parent.
但是我们可以在gdb中将follow fork模式设置为child，当我们现在继续并发送
the long input, we get the segfault.
Awesome, now you have everything in place to develop the full exploit.